{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "A candy manufacturer that made candy at a lower cost without improving the quality of the candy could be said to ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Lowering cost is a measure of increased efficiency. Making better candy is a measure of increased effectiveness. So lowering cost for unimproved candy shows an increase in efficiency but not effectiveness."
    },
    {
      "question": "A candy manufacturer would increase both efficiency and effectiveness by making ________.",
      "answer": "better candy at a lower cost",
      "explanation": "Increasing efficiency involves making the product at lower cost. Increasing effectiveness means making a better product. So increasing efficiency and effectiveness would entail making a better product at a lower cost. Any other combination of the two variables—not improving the cost or the quality of the candy—would not be an improvement in both efficiency and effectiveness."
    },
    {
      "question": "A goal of efficiency is to minimize output costs while maximizing input costs.",
      "answer": "False",
      "explanation": "The goal of efficiency is the opposite—to maximize outputs while minimizing inputs. An efficient operation uses the fewest resources to generate the greatest amount of product."
    },
    {
      "question": "A small business manager in many ways combines the roles of top manager and first-line manager in a large business.",
      "answer": "True",
      "explanation": "The goal of efficiency is the opposite—to maximize outputs while minimizing inputs. An efficient operation uses the fewest resources to generate the greatest amount of product."
    },
    {
      "question": "A typical first-level manager spends more of his or her time leading than planning.",
      "answer": "True",
      "explanation": "Of the three managerial levels, first-level managers proportionally spend the most time leading and the least time planning. Typically, first-level managers spend about twice as much time leading as they do planning."
    },
    {
      "question": "All organizations have ________ that define(s) the organization's purpose and reason for existing.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "An organization's goals define its purpose and reason for existing. For example, the goals of a bank might be to make money, while the goals of a church choir might to be to create beautiful music. Rules can help an organization achieve its goals, but rules do not explicitly define those goals. Organizational structure defines and limits how people within an organization interact, but structure on its own is not something that serves to define an organization's purpose."
    },
    {
      "question": "Among the trends in the new workplace, one can expect to find __________.",
      "answer": "more valuing people as human assets",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "An effective manager achieves both high-performance results and high levels of _________ among people doing the required work.",
      "answer": "satisfaction",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "An important part of the controlling function is ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Once tasks are assigned and work is ongoing, a manager must assess the performance of organization members to see if the work is being carried out successfully. Structuring and coordinating are subfunctions of the organizing function. In extreme cases, punishment might be considered a part of controlling, but evaluating is clearly a much more common part of the controlling function."
    },
    {
      "question": "An organization is ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "By definition, an organization is a deliberate arrangement of people who have a common purpose or goal. An organization may or may not exist in a discrete physical location. For example, many of today's political advocacy organizations exist largely as online entities without a primary physical location. Though some people in an organization may perform similar tasks, many do not. For example, doctors and administrators may both work for the same hospital organization but perform very different tasks. Finally, focus on profit does not determine an organization. Many organizations, such as a bird-watching club, do not include profit as a goal."
    },
    {
      "question": "Another term for effectiveness is ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Effectiveness is said to be 'doing the right things' because effectiveness is concerned with obtaining results and reaching goals. Doing things 'in the right way' results in efficiency rather than effectiveness. Note that an enterprise can be effective—i.e., it can attain goals—without being efficient in such areas as keeping costs and resources down. Doing things intelligently is clearly part of an effective effort without being critical to it. The same can be said of doing things when necessary—it is not a critical part of an effective effort."
    },
    {
      "question": "Another term for efficiency is ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Efficiency is often termed doing things right because the phrase denotes the manner in which tasks are carried out. The 'right' way or efficient way correlates with a minimum of wasted time, money, energy, and resources. 'Doing the right things,' on the other hand, refers to effectiveness, not efficiency. Making sure that things get done and doing things at the right time are both often part of an efficient undertaking, but neither effort could be said to define efficiency."
    },
    {
      "question": "Brenda Kraft has proven herself to be an able manager. Her section has a high project completion rate with the highest-quality product and the lowest defects in her division. In addition, she accomplishes this with fewer full-time people than other managers. Co-workers say that the secret of her success is in her ability to delegate responsibility and her understanding of the basic 'management processes.' Brenda's ability to delegate responsibility well is evidence that she excels at which management function?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Delegating responsibility falls under the category of organizing. Good organizers excel at determining the right job for the right person. Planning may include a minor element of delegating, as a planner must map out future tasks. Leading includes an element of directing, which also involves delegating. However, neither planning nor leading is as directly involved in delegating as organizing is. Finally, controlling, largely a monitoring activity, has little to do with delegating."
    },
    {
      "question": "Determining who reports to whom is part of the controlling function of management.",
      "answer": "False",
      "explanation": "The controlling function is largely a process of monitoring and evaluation. Subordinates are observed to see if they are working efficiently. Programs are evaluated to make sure they are progressing toward organizational goals. Deciding who reports to whom is not a part of this function."
    },
    {
      "question": "Effectiveness is synonymous with ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Effectiveness is concerned with ends as opposed to means. Being effective means 'getting the job done' (attaining goals), while being efficient is concerned with 'how the job got done' and such things as cost minimization. While effective operations usually feature smart management, the two are not necessarily synonymous."
    },
    {
      "question": "Effectiveness refers to the attainment of the organization's goals.",
      "answer": "True",
      "explanation": "Effectiveness is concerned with 'doing the right things'—choosing the tasks that will help the organization achieve its goals. Efficiency, on the other hand, refers to 'doing things right,' that is, once tasks are chosen they are done with a minimum of waste."
    },
    {
      "question": "Good management strives for ________.",
      "answer": "high efficiency and high effectiveness",
      "explanation": "High efficiency and high effectiveness are both things that managers seek to obtain. High efficiency is associated with minimal waste and a  aximum of production. High effectiveness is associated with success in achieving goals. Low or moderate measures of efficiency or effectiveness are clearly inferior to a high amount of each quality."
    },
    {
      "question": "Brenda Kraft has proven herself to be an able manager. Her section has a high project completion rate with the highest-quality product and the lowest defects in her division. In addition, she accomplishes this with fewer full-time people than other managers. Co-workers say that the secret of her success is in her ability to delegate responsibility and her understanding of the basic 'management processes.' \n If Brenda accomplished her projects on time with high-quality results, but she took more time than other managers in the process, you could say that as a manager she was ________.",
      "answer": "effective, but not efficient",
      "explanation": "Accomplishing goals makes Brenda effective. Taking too much time makes Brenda inefficient. These two qualities—high quality results coupled with longer than normal delivery times—say nothing about Brenda's ability to be a leader."
    },
    {
      "question": "In a small organization, which of the following is NOT likely to be true?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "A small firm is typically more flexible, less formal, less structured, and less complex than a large firm. Planning in a small firm is likely to be a freewheeling affair rather than follow a rigid protocol. One thing you would not see in a small firm would be computerized monitoring systems. Instead, you would expect monitoring to be done on a more personal basis, with plenty of opportunity for employees to rectify any mistakes they make."
    },
    {
      "question": "In Katz’s framework, top managers tend to rely more on their _________ skills than do first-line managers.",
      "answer": "conceptual",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Managers who are effective at meeting organizational goals always act efficiently.",
      "answer": "False",
      "explanation": "A manager may be effective but not efficient. For example, a manager may excel at achieving goals but waste a lot of money, energy, and resources in achieving them."
    },
    {
      "question": "Non-profit organizations are different from for-profit organizations primarily ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "The big difference between for-profit and non-profit organizations is the way they keep score or measure success. For-profit organizations usually look at the bottom line—how much profit they make—as a way to measure success. Non-profits look at more varied metrics: a school may look at how well students test; a soup kitchen may look at how many people they help, and so on. The way organizations make decisions, motivate employees, and hire employees is virtually the same for both for-profit and non-profit organizations."
    },
    {
      "question": "Of the following, which is the lowest level of management?",
      "answer": "a middle manager",
      "explanation": "The middle manager represents the lowest managerial position among the choices given here, but it is not the lowest position in the managerial hierarchy. Individual  who rank above a middle manager include a vice president and an individual who defines organizational philosophy, both of whom would qualify as top managers. Finally, a nonmanagerial employee is lowest in the hierarchy among these choices, but this individual is not a part of management."
    },
    {
      "question": "One of the common characteristics of all organizations is ________ that define(s) rules, regulations, and values of the organization.",
      "answer": "a systematic structure",
      "explanation": "An organization's structure identifies organizational values that include behavioral standards, customs, ethical mores, and conventions that delineate relationships between organization members. The structure of an organization need not be formally written as bylaws. The goals and purpose of an organization can influence its values, but neither of these items can be said to define an organization's values."
    },
    {
      "question": "Organizing includes ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "The key part of the organizing function requires the manager to assign tasks to different organization members. For example, a bicycle racing team's manager will assign roles for each rider to cover during a race. Defining goals is a planning function, while resolving conflicts and  motivating are both part of the leadership function."
    },
    {
      "question": "Performance efficiency is a measure of the _________ associated with task accomplishment.",
      "answer": "resource costs",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Productivity is a measure of the quantity and _________ of work produced, with resource utilization taken into account.",
      "answer": "quality",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Providing motivation is part of the controlling function of management.",
      "answer": "False",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Resolving a conflict would be considered to fall under which managerial function?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Conflict resolution is thought to fall under the leading function. Controlling is defined largely as a monitoring function and does not include resolving conflicts. Resolving conflicts is also not a subfunction of planning. Finally, directing is not one of the four major functions and is actually part of leading itself."
    },
    {
      "question": "The accounting manager for a local newspaper would be considered a _________ manager, whereas the plant manager in a manufacturing firm would be considered a __________ manager.",
      "answer": "general, functional",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The controlling management function is largely a matter of ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Resolving conflicts falls under the category of leading, while determining what needs to be done is an organizing task. A minor part of controlling may involve enforcing of employee rules, but monitoring represents a much better choice, as the main goal of controlling is to make sure that tasks are being accomplished as planned."
    },
    {
      "question": "The four contemporary management processes are planning, organizing, leading, and commanding.",
      "answer": "False",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The management function of __________ is being performed when a retail manager measures daily sales in the women’s apparel department and compares them with daily sales targets.",
      "answer": "controlling",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The manager’s role in the “upside-down pyramid” view of organizations is best described as providing __________ so that operating workers can directly serve _________.",
      "answer": "support, customers",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The primary job of a manager is to ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Though managers may make important decisions, tackle difficult tasks, or coordinate between leaders and lower-level employees, a manager's primary job is to supervise the work of others. The supervisory role is what distinguishes managers from nonmanagers."
    },
    {
      "question": "The process of building and maintaining good working relationships with others who may help implement a manager’s work agendas is called __________.",
      "answer": "networking",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The process of management involves the functions of planning, _________ leading, and controlling.",
      "answer": "organizing",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The requirement that a manager answer to a higher-level boss for results achieved by a work team is called __________.",
      "answer": "authority?",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The research of Mintzberg and others concludes that managers __________.",
      "answer": "always live with the pressures of performance responsibility",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The work of a manager ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "The primary job of a manager is to oversee work of others. However, this does not preclude a manager from performing tasks on his or her own that do not involve supervision of others. An example of a manager not being limited to supervising would be an art director at a book company who supervises work of others but also creates artworks on her own. Tasks performed by managers are not necessarily high level and may involve interaction with nonmanagerial workers, so neither of these choices is correct."
    },
    {
      "question": "Today, the basic management functions are considered to be ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "The four functions are planning, organizing, leading, and controlling. The other choices include part of these functions (coordinating is a part of planning; monitoring is a part of controlling; motivating is a part of leading; and decision making is a key part of all managerial functions)."
    },
    {
      "question": "Unlike the manager of a small business, the most important concerns of a manager in a large organization are focused ________.",
      "answer": "internally, particularly on the allocation of resources",
      "explanation": "Resource allocation is typically the most important concern for a manager in a large organization. For example, goals and structural issues in a large car company are likely to be well worked out, causing the manager to focus on apportioning the organization's ample resources wisely with respect to commitments of time, funds, manpower, and creative energy. Creation of new business opportunities are much less likely to be needed in a large firm than in a small one as the large firm may have entire departments devoted to that task."
    },
    {
      "question": "Don Sakaguchi, manager at Control Systems, Inc., sighs as he sips his coffee at 5 A.M. and reads his agenda for the day. Don's first duty is to preside over a retirement party for a beloved employee and say a few words on her behalf. Next, he will give a tour to a news reporter who is writing a story on the new plant expansion. Don then has a meeting with the unit manager, Phil Johnson, to discuss Phil's recent performance drop (a task Don always hates). Finally, in the late afternoon, Don will be reviewing the recent equipment malfunction and deciding whether to deploy extra people to get the equipment running as soon as possible. What a day! \nWhat kind of a manager is Don likely to be?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Don's appearance at the party and role as host to the reporter suggest that he is clearly above the level of first-line manager and low-level middle manager. Don is too involved with everyday activities (Phil's problem and equipment malfunction) to be a top CEO. All of this evidence suggests that Don is a fairly high-level middle manager—a plant manager."
    },
    {
      "question": "When a team leader clarifies desired work targets and deadlines for a work team, he or she is fulfilling the management function of __________.",
      "answer": "delegating?",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "As a production supervisor, Joe determines the number of output units his department will produce each week. On Monday, he informs his team that the schedule is going to be difficult this week due to the increased number of output units. He goes on to tell them that he is confident that they can fulfill the schedule because they are tough, talented, and 'when the going gets tough, they are the ones who get going.' Each day during the week, Joe checks the amount of output that the employees have completed and the number of units that have been rejected. \nWhen Joe checks the amount of output units that the team has completed and the number of units that have been rejected, he is performing which management process?",
      "answer": "controlling",
      "explanation": "Controlling involves monitoring ongoing tasks and evaluating them to see if they are proceeding as planned. Since Joe is both monitoring and evaluating, the function he is performing is controlling. Leading, planning, and organizing do not have an explicit monitoring component, so controlling is the only function that fits here."
    },
    {
      "question": "As a production supervisor, Joe determines the number of output units his department will produce each week. On Monday, he informs his team that the schedule is going to be difficult this week due to the increased number of output units. He goes on to tell them that he is confident that they can fulfill the schedule because they are tough, talented, and 'when the going gets tough, they are the ones who get going.' Each day during the  eek, Joe checks the amount of output that the employees have completed and the number of units that have been rejected. \nWhen Joe decides the number of output units his team will be able to produce this week, which management process is he performing?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Planning involves foreseeing the future and making accommodations to deal with what is likely to occur. Joe is performing both of these functions, so he is planning. None of the other choices involve specifically preparing for future occurrences, so planning is the only category that fits here."
    },
    {
      "question": "As a production supervisor, Joe determines the number of output units his department will produce each week. On Monday, he informs his team that the schedule is going to be difficult this week due to the increased number of output units. He goes on to tell them that he is confident that they can fulfill the schedule because they are tough, talented, and 'when the going gets tough, they are the ones who get going.' Each day during the week, Joe checks the amount of output that the employees have completed and the number of units that have been rejected. \nWhen Joe tells the employees that he is sure they can fulfill the schedule because they are the ones 'who get going when the going is tough,' he is performing which management process?",
      "answer": "leading",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "When someone with a negative attitude toward minorities makes a decision to deny advancement opportunities to a Hispanic worker, this is an example of __________.",
      "answer": "discrimination",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which management challenge refers to management's responsibility to be attentive to environmental and societal challenges?",
      "answer": "sustainability",
      "explanation": "From a business perspective, sustainability has been defined as a company's ability to achieve its business goals and increase long-term shareholder value by integrating economic, environmental, and social opportunities into its business strategies."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a key difference between managerial and nonmanagerial employees?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "The distinction between managerial and nonmanagerial employees resides solely in overseeing work. Managers have the responsibility of supervising and directing work of others. Nonmanagerial employees do not have this responsibility. Managers may or may not receive better compensation, have more education, or work longer hours than nonmanagers—so none of these criteria can serve to distinguish between the two."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following levels of management is associated with positions such as executive vice president, chief operating officer, chief executive officer, and chairperson of the board?",
      "answer": "top managers",
      "explanation": "All of the titles listed above—executive vice president, chief operating officer, chief executive officer, and chairperson of the board—are executive positions that are typically part of an organization's top management. Team leaders are types of first-line managers and are not part of top management. Any positions that include executive as part of the title would eliminate middle managers as a choice."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following might be an example of increased efficiency in manufacturing?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Efficiency must involve reducing the input-to-output ratio in some way. Cutting the amount of labor reduces the amount of input and so marks an increase in efficiency. Cutting the price does not affect the amount of resources and labor that go into the product, nor does it improve the product itself, so it is not an efficiency measure. Increasing sales and advertising similarly do not change the input-output ratio so they do not increase efficiency."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following types of managers is responsible for making organization-wide decisions and establishing the plans and goals that affect the entire organization?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "In a typical management hierarchy, the individuals responsible for making higher-order decisions that involve planning, goals, policy, and philosophy are the top managers. Team leaders are generally first-line managers at the bottom of the hierarchy who are least involved with higher-order goals. Department heads and project leaders are titles for middle managers who are more involved with the implementation rather than the making of goals and policy."
    },
    {
      "question": "_________ managers pay special attention to the external environment, looking for problems and opportunities and finding ways to deal with them.",
      "answer": "Top",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Remedies that all renewal strategies employ include which of the following?",
      "answer": "cutting costs",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The first three steps of the strategic management process involve ________ strategies.",
      "answer": "planning",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following do managers NOT typically use to formulate strategies?",
      "answer": "არა - finding ways to exploit the organization's strengths",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A company that looks for a niche in the market is following which strategy?",
      "answer": "focus",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A company whose goal is to retain its ideal size and market share is employing which kind of strategy?",
      "answer": "stability",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A company with a differentiation strategy focuses on making its products or services ________.",
      "answer": "unique and special",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A company with a stability strategy will plan to dramatically increase market share in a highly competitive market.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A corporate strategy focuses primarily on ________.",
      "answer": "an organization's mission",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A corporate strategy may be a growth strategy, a stability strategy, or a renewal strategy.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A cost leadership competitive strategy focuses on which of the following?",
      "answer": "efficiency",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A differentiation strategy ________.",
      "answer": "can focus on a brand image",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A diversification strategy focuses on a company becoming its own supplier of inputs.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A diversified corporation is likely to have ________.",
      "answer": "multiple competitive strategies",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A focus strategy seeks to appeal to a narrow segment of a market.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A mission statement does NOT include which of the following?",
      "answer": "major competitors",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A mission statement for a kayak manufacturer might be as follows: To make the highest-quality kayaks and sell them at a competitive price.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A mission statement includes identification of an organization's ________.",
      "answer": "purpose and basic philosophy",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A salad dressing company that buys a large olive grove to produce olive oil is practicing which of the following?",
      "answer": "backward vertical integration",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A sneaker company creating its own stores where it sells only its own brand is an example of which of the following?",
      "answer": "forward vertical integration",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Michael Porter, a company with good products that has no clear competitive advantage is said to be ________.",
      "answer": "stuck in the middle",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "All of the following are threats to a sustainable, long-term competitive advantage EXCEPT ________.",
      "answer": "market stability",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "An external analysis will identify the threats to a company's well-being, but not opportunities for success.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "An external analysis, the second step of the strategic management process, helps identify ________.",
      "answer": "a company's opportunities and threats",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "An internal analysis, the third step of the strategic management process helps identify ________.",
      "answer": "resources and capabilities",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "An organization's capabilities identify ________.",
      "answer": "what the organization can do",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "An organization's resources identify ________.",
      "answer": "what the organization has",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Competitive advantages for a high-prestige, premium coffee franchise like Starbucks are likely to include all of the following EXCEPT ________.",
      "answer": "lowest prices",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Core competencies include an organization's major capabilities and its resources.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Customer service cannot be considered a strategic weapon for an organization.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "General Mills expanding its line so that it sells several different types of Cheerios is an example of which of the following?",
      "answer": "concentration",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Growth strategies include ________.",
      "answer": "vertical integration, horizontal integration, concentration, diversification",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Imagine that you are the president of Taco Rocket, a new and successful chain of 8 Mexican fast-food restaurants. The success you have experienced in the last 5 years has you thinking of what to do with the business next. Should you expand the business at the current rate? Open new and different restaurants? What? Up to now your success has been based on selling high-quality tacos and burritos at a price that others can't match. Your business is pursuing which of Porter's strategies?",
      "answer": "cost leadership strategy",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Imagine that you are the president of Taco Rocket, a new and successful chain of 8 Mexican fast-food restaurants. The success you have experienced in the last 5 years has you thinking of what to do with the business next. Should you expand the business at the current rate? Open new and different restaurants? What? You are thinking of buying a tortilla factory in a nearby state. This action would be an example of ________.",
      "answer": "backward vertical integration",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Imagine that you are the president of Taco Rocket, a new and successful chain of 8 Mexican fast-food restaurants. The success you have experienced in the last 5 years has you thinking of what to do with the business next. Should you expand the business at the current rate? Open new and different restaurants? What? Recently, Taco Rocket has considered buying a local competitor and the two would combine under the Taco Rocket name. This is an example of which of the following?",
      "answer": "horizontal integration",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Imagine that you are the president of Taco Rocket, a new and successful chain of 8 Mexican fast-food restaurants. The success you have experienced in the last 5 years has you thinking of what to do with the business next. Should you expand the business at the current rate? Open new and different restaurants? What? For a limited time, Taco Rocket is thinking of coming out with a new Fifth Degree Burrito that is so hot it 'burns a hole in the plate.' Catering to the small segment of the market that likes super-hot food is an example of a ________.",
      "answer": "focus strategy",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In forward vertical integration, a company becomes its own ________, while in backward vertical integration, the company is its own ________.",
      "answer": "distributor; supplier",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Innovation and super-high quality are typically the keys to a cost-leadership strategy.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Most successful companies find that ________ a competitive advantage is almost as difficult as developing a competitive advantage.",
      "answer": "sustaining",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Once SWOT analysis is complete, managers ________ to address the issues that came up during the analysis.",
      "answer": "formulate strategies",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Strategic management is the act of figuring out how an organization will compete in the marketplace and attract loyal customers.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "SWOT analysis combines ________.",
      "answer": "external and internal analyses",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "SWOT analysis identifies and analyzes an organization's ________.",
      "answer": "strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "SWOT analysis includes the identification of an organization's strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The first step in the six-step strategic management process is to ________.",
      "answer": "identify the organization's mission",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The first step in the strategic management process is analyzing the external environment.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The thing that makes your product special is known as your ________.",
      "answer": "competitive advantage",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The three different types of strategies that managers implement are ________.",
      "answer": "corporate, competitive, functional",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The ________ strategy occupies the level below the corporate strategy.",
      "answer": "competitive",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "This term describes an electric shaver company that carefully observes its competitor's production line to look for ways to improve its own manufacturing process.",
      "answer": "benchmarking",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "To address limited, short-term problems, a company is most likely to employ a ________ strategy.",
      "answer": "retrenchment",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "To create a competitive advantage that is sustainable, a company can begin by focusing on quality, then ________",
      "answer": "make incremental improvements to keep quality levels high",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "To gain a sustainable competitive advantage, a pharmaceutical company might ________.",
      "answer": "secure exclusive rights to produce a drug",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Troubled companies seek ________ to address serious problems.",
      "answer": "renewal strategies",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Two movie studios combining to form one larger studio is an example of which of the following?",
      "answer": "horizontal integration",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "When Google purchased YouTube, a company that featured different, but related products, Google was engaging in which of the following?",
      "answer": "diversification",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes a company that is following a focus strategy?",
      "answer": "a software company that makes financial products for accountants only",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following makes up the three main types of corporate strategies?",
      "answer": "growth, stability, renewal",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following would you expect to find in a clothing store that follows a cost leadership strategy?",
      "answer": "basic, no frills, practical items",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A cell phone company might ask managers to do some environmental scanning of blogs that deal with electronics as a way to ________.",
      "answer": "identify emerging trends",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A key function of planning is to create goals.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A major strength of formal planning is that it reinforces past successes and incorporates them into the future.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A politician whose ultimate goal is to get elected is planning campaign ads for TV. In planning the ads, the politician is functioning at a ________ level.",
      "answer": "tactical",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A six-month plan qualifies as a short-term plan.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "All managers plan in some way, either formally or informally.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "An organization that fails to plan will find it hard to assess progress.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "An organization's real goals and priorities are best revealed by ________.",
      "answer": "its actions in the marketplace",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "As long as people have goals, how they are set them doesn’t really make much of an impact on their success.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "British Petroleum uses scenario planning to explore what the company would do if and when its oil supplies run out. For BP, the benefits of scenario planning include which of the following?",
      "answer": "All of the above.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Buying a competitor's product for evaluation is a form of environmental scanning.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Company LMN, a toy manufacturer, has discovered that one of its suppliers has used lead based paint on one of its products. It is Thanksgiving week. The Executive committee has assembled a team to devise a plan to mitigate the issue. LMN is using ____________",
      "answer": "Tactical planning",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Effective time management includes all of the following except:",
      "answer": "Do not leave details for others to address or for later",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Formal planning typically leads to which of the following?",
      "answer": "higher profits",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Goals are documents that outline how plans are to be carried out.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Goals typically should be reserved for managers only. Goals should not be shared with subordinates.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Good planning improves focus and flexibility.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In a means-ends chain, a goal at a lower level ________.",
      "answer": "is the bridge to a goal at the next higher level",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In addition to being made by both managers and employees, MBO goals must be ________.",
      "answer": "specific and include an explicit time limit",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In formal planning, ________.",
      "answer": "specific goals covering a period of years are defined",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In general, upper-level managers focus on tactical or operational planning.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In management by objectives (MBO), goals ________.",
      "answer": "are jointly determined by employees and managers",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In most cases, strategic goals include ________.",
      "answer": "all objectives that are not financial",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In order to make effective goals, they should be specific, timely, measurable, challenging, and attainable.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In reality, all organizations have ________.",
      "answer": "multiple goals",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In the planning process, __________ refer to the specific results or desired outcomes that one intends to achieve.",
      "answer": "Objectives",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In the twenty-first century, managers increasingly need to consider their plans as ________.",
      "answer": "flexible road maps with destinations that may change",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In traditional goal setting, as they work their way from top management to employees, goals are likely to ________.",
      "answer": "become less clear",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In traditional goal setting, these individuals set goals.",
      "answer": "top managers",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Informal planning typically works better in large organizations.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Long-term plans used to refer to plans that covered a period of over three years, but now it refers to any time period over one year.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Making sure the most important things get first attention is an example of ____________.",
      "answer": "Priority orientation",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "MBO programs usually are successful largely because they ________.",
      "answer": "give employees a sense of ownership of goals",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Most managers feel that formal, top-down plans created by corporate planning departments are ________.",
      "answer": "usually unsatisfactory",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "One criticism of formal planning is that it focuses on how to beat the competition rather than how to ________.",
      "answer": "focus on new opportunities",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Organizations that don't formally plan may be more likely to have ________.",
      "answer": "multiple departments performing the same task",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Organizations that set ___________ do so knowing these goals will be difficult to reach and require extra hard work.",
      "answer": "Stretch goals",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Planning gives organizations a way to deal with change that ________.",
      "answer": "reduces uncertainty",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Planning gives organizations direction that primarily helps them ________.",
      "answer": "improve teamwork and coordinate activities",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Planning is concerned with ________.",
      "answer": "both ends and means",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Planning provides direction to managers and nonmanagers alike.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Planning rarely improves teamwork and cooperation among employees.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Planning that identifies alternative courses of action that can be implemented to meet the needs of changing circumstances is called __________.",
      "answer": "Contingency planning.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Prioritizing your activities for the day could include items considered to be: Most important, Important, Least Important and Not Important.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Setting objectives and determining how they will be accomplished is the essence of the management function of __________.",
      "answer": "Planning.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Standing plans typically can be used ________.",
      "answer": "repeatedly",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Strategic plans address ________.",
      "answer": "overall organizational goals",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Successful planning depends more on whether managers plan than on the quality of their planning.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Tactical plans are operational plans that identify ________.",
      "answer": "how overall goals are to be achieved",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The breadth of a plan refers to ________ concerns.",
      "answer": "strategic versus tactical",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The commitment concept states that plans should ________.",
      "answer": "stake out a time period that is neither too long nor too short",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The four reasons that organizations plan are to establish coordinated effort, set standards, minimize waste, and reduce uncertainty and the impact of change.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The key to MBO, or management by objectives, is that managers and subordinates mutually agree on goals.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The more uncertain a situation is, the more ________ plans must be.",
      "answer": "flexible",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The purpose of __________ is to find out what other people and organizations are doing very well, and planning how to incorporate these ideas into one’s own operations.",
      "answer": "Benchmarking",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The specificity of a plan refers to ________ concerns.",
      "answer": "specific versus directional",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Top managers, for the most part, focus on this type of planning.",
      "answer": "strategic",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Traditional goal setting requires top managers to set goals that are carried out by the organizational levels below.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which goal-setting sequence is correct for the following steps?",
      "answer": "3, 1, 2, 4, 6, 5",
      "explanation": "review the mission, evaluate resources, identify goals, communicate goals, build feedback, link rewards to goals."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which level of management spends more time with long-range planning when compared to other levels of management?",
      "answer": "Top-level managers.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following best defines goals?",
      "answer": "desired outcomes for the future",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following best defines plans?",
      "answer": "documents that describe how goals will be met",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an example of a strategic goal for a professional baseball team?",
      "answer": "to average over 90 wins a year for the next 5 years",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a function of planning?",
      "answer": "settling disputes between employees",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a reason for managers to plan?",
      "answer": "to establish responsibility for mistakes",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following might mostly be criticism of formal planning?",
      "answer": "Plans lock organizations into rigid goals and timetables.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements accurately describe planning time horizons?",
      "answer": "All of the above.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements accurately describes the benefits of planning?",
      "answer": "A, B, and C.",
      "explanation": "ყველა სწორია"
    },
    {
      "question": "________ are important because they provide the standards against which all organizational accomplishments are measured.",
      "answer": "Goals",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ communicate broad guidelines for making decisions and taking action in specific circumstances.",
      "answer": "Policies",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The primary purpose of an organization structure is to design job titles for different workers and to assign daily work tasks to them.",
      "answer": "False",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Given a clear mission, core values, objectives and strategy, organizing begins the process of strategy implementation by clarifying jobs and working relationships.",
      "answer": "True",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Empowerment gives synergy a chance by joining with others to get things done; allowing and even helping them to do things that you might be very good at doing yourself.",
      "answer": "True",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Organizations that are set up with a central core that is linked with outside contractors and suppliers of essential business services are called __________ structures.",
      "answer": "Network.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In a highly centralized organization, one would expect to find __________.",
      "answer": "A concentration of decision making with top management.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A(n) __________ operates in a shifting network of external strategic alliances that are engaged as needed, and typically are supported by extensive information technology (IT) utilization.",
      "answer": "Virtual organization.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A(n) _________ groups together people who work on the same product or process, serve similar customers, or work in the same area or geographic region.",
      "answer": "Divisional structure.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A __________ organization eliminates internal boundaries among parts and external boundaries linking with the external environment.",
      "answer": "Boundaryless",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A matrix structure basically combines elements of __________and __________ structures.",
      "answer": "Functional and divisional.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A finance manager who reads the Wall Street Journal on a regular basis would be performing which role?",
      "answer": "monitor",
      "explanation": "One of the responsibilities of a finance manager would be to keep track or monitor important events taking place in the business world. Reading the Wall Street Journal would be a good way to do this. After reading, the manager might disseminate some of the information he learned, but this would be secondary to the information monitoring function. A leader or liaison may indeed read a newspaper but only in the function of being an information monitor."
    },
    {
      "question": "A pharmaceutical company manager attending a meeting of academic scientists would be functioning in which role?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "A liaison functions as a link from one organization to another. In this case, the manager would be linking her for-profit organization to an organization that might provide it with valuable expertise or information. The other choices here are all somewhat valid as the manager would need to procure information, represent her company, and make decisions. However, the liaison role is a much better fit for this situation."
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Katz, the four critical managerial skills can be classified as ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Empirical skills are not a part of Katz's scheme. Controlling is a Fayol category for managerial function, not a Katz skill category."
    },
    {
      "question": "All of the following are examples of informational roles according to Mintzberg EXCEPT ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "The role of an entrepreneur in an organization is typically to identify and procure new business opportunities. In Mintzberg's scheme, an entrepreneur takes on a decisional role in deciding where to look for opportunities and which ones to invest in. The other three choices here—monitor, disseminator, and spokesperson—are informational in nature. A monitor keeps track of information. Both a disseminator and spokesperson distribute information."
    },
    {
      "question": "Almost all managerial tasks involve ________.",
      "answer": "decision making",
      "explanation": "Some managerial tasks, such as motivating store employees, require little or no technical skill or long-term planning. Employee motivation employs a modicum of political skill—e.g., to enlist people to your cause—but a high-level political skill is generally not required. What can't be avoided at all levels of management is the necessity of making decisions. The manager trying to motivate employees, for example, must decide on the appropriate 'carrots and sticks' to get his or her people to perform successfully."
    },
    {
      "question": "Brenda Kraft has proven herself to be an able manager. Her section has a high project completion rate with the highest-quality product and the lowest defects in her division. In addition, she accomplishes this with fewer full-time people than other managers. Co-workers say that the secret of her success is in her ability to delegate responsibility and her understanding of the basic 'management processes.'Brenda's high project completion rate indicates that she is ________.",
      "answer": "an effective manager",
      "explanation": "Completing a high number of projects is accomplishing a goal. Goal-accomplishment is a measure of the effectiveness of a manager. 'An efficient manager' is incorrect because completing projects says nothing about how efficient Brenda is. In a similar way, 'a good spokesperson' and 'a good resource allocator' are not correct as there is no indication in the paragraph of Brenda's skill as an information provider (spokesperson) or decision-maker (resource allocator)."
    },
    {
      "question": "Compared to the manager of a large organization, a small business manager is more likely to be a(n) ________.",
      "answer": "generalist",
      "explanation": "The nature of a small business requires its managers to be generalists and take on multiple roles that would be assumed by separate individuals in larger firms. For example, the manager of a bike shop might need to function as a long-range planner, salesperson, spokesperson, and task supervisor all at the same time. This requirement of versatility would rule out being a specialist. Though a small firm manager may function exclusively as a figurehead and information monitor from time to time, a more accurate description of his or her job would be as a generalist."
    },
    {
      "question": "Designing a series of interview questions to provide information about possible customers for a company would primarily require ________.",
      "answer": "conceptual skills",
      "explanation": "Designing interview questions would certainly require some degree of both interpersonal and political skills. However, the main challenge of the problem is to think through the complex situation of who would make a likely customer for a product. Therefore, conceptual skills would be of the highest priority for this task. The task would require little, if any, technical skills as writing the questions could be easily accomplished with a simple word-processing program or pencil and paper."
    },
    {
      "question": "Good political skills would be most important to a manager who ________.            ",
      "answer": "wants to rise through organizational ranks",
      "explanation": "Those who seek job security, fair pay, or a lighter workload do not need a network of allies within an organization to accomplish their goals. So they are much less in need of political skills than a manager who is ambitious and wants to rise through the company ranks. The ambitious manager needs supporters and can only acquire them by employing his or her political skills."
    },
    {
      "question": "Michelle is the general manager of a power plant. This morning, she will meet with city officials to discuss environmental issues. After the meeting, she will confer with the plant's section managers to address the concerns of the city representatives. This afternoon, Michelle will meet with a team leader to go over a complaint filed by an employee. After the complaint meeting, Michelle plans to spend time in the library and on the Internet researching new technologies that can be used to improve the performance of her plant. Michelle's evaluation of new technologies that can be used in the production processes of her plant is an example of which type of management skill?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "In evaluating new technologies, Michelle must break down and sort out a great deal of complex information and come to some conclusion about how some of it might be applied to her own situation. This is clearly an example of conceptual skill—analyzing a complex situation. The task does not require Michelle to communicate her conclusions at this point or use them in a social or political context. So the clear choice here is that Michelle is using conceptual skill"
    },
    {
      "question": "Technical skills involve a manager's ability to think logically and effectively about abstract situations.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": "Thinking logically about abstract situations is a conceptual skill rather than a technical skill."
    },
    {
      "question": "Technical skills might include ________.            ",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Technical skills typically involve the mastery of some kind of specialized technology or technique that is helpful for a job. Verbal skills and writing ability are too general to qualify as 'technical.' Decision-making ability does not involve a special technology or technique. Computer programming, though more common today than it was in previous decades, best qualifies as a technical skill"
    },
    {
      "question": "The managerial role that changes the least between middle and top managers is ________.            ",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "According to the studies summarized in the text, planning is the category that increases most, going from 18% of a manager's time to 28%. This is followed by organizing, which increases from 33% to 36%. Leading, in fact, decreases rather than increases by 14%. The category that increases least is controlling, which goes from 13% to 14%."
    },
    {
      "question": "Under which category would you classify skill in motivating subordinates?            ",
      "answer": "interpersonal skills",
      "explanation": "Conceptual and technical skills are too abstract and impersonal to qualify as a classification for motivational skill. Motivating people can feature a considerable amount of political skill. However, motivation is less about manipulating a power base within an organization than it is in simply relating well to other people, so interpersonal skills is the best choice for this question."
    },
    {
      "question": "Don Sakaguchi, manager at Control Systems, Inc., sighs as he sips his coffee at 5 A.M. and reads his agenda for the day. Don's first duty is to preside over a retirement party for a beloved employee and say a few words on her behalf. Next, he will give a tour to a news reporter who is writing a story on the new plant expansion. Don then has a meeting with the unit manager, Phil Johnson, to discuss Phil's recent performance drop (a task Don always hates). Finally, in the late afternoon, Don will be reviewing the recent equipment malfunction and deciding whether to deploy extra people to get the equipment running as soon as possible. What a day! What role will Don be performing when he gives the plant tour to the newspaper reporter?",
      "answer": "spokesperson",
      "explanation": "Giving a tour to a newspaper reporter is an informational role. Don will be showcasing the features of the new plant expansion. This role of speaking for the company fits that of a spokesperson. Giving a tour is not a way of procuring new business opportunities, so it is not an entrepreneurial role. Don is not checking on ongoing tasks, so he is not functioning as a monitor. Finally, Don is speaking rather than making decisions, so he is not functioning in the role of resource allocator."
    },
    {
      "question": "Don Sakaguchi, manager at Control Systems, Inc., sighs as he sips his coffee at 5 A.M. and reads his agenda for the day. Don's first duty is to preside over a retirement party for a beloved employee and say a few words on her behalf. Next, he will give a tour to a news reporter who is writing a story on the new plant expansion. Don then has a meeting with the unit manager, Phil Johnson, to discuss Phil's recent performance drop (a task Don always hates). Finally, in the late afternoon, Don will be reviewing the recent equipment malfunction and deciding whether to deploy extra people to get the equipment running as soon as possible. What a day!When Don attends the retirement party, he will be operating in which of the management roles?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Don's appearance at the party is largely a ceremonial role—he is representing the organization during an important event—so he is performing the role of a figurehead. Don is not specifically providing motivation for employees, so he is not functioning as a leader. He is not linking to the outside world, so his role does not fit that of a liaison. Finally, he is not evaluating or keeping track of tasks, so he is not functioning in the role of a monitor."
    },
    {
      "question": "Don Sakaguchi, manager at Control Systems, Inc., sighs as he sips his coffee at 5 A.M. and reads his agenda for the day. Don's first duty is to preside over a retirement party for a beloved employee and say a few words on her behalf. Next, he will give a tour to a news reporter who is writing a story on the new plant expansion. Don then has a meeting with the unit manager, Phil Johnson, to discuss Phil's recent performance drop (a task Don always hates). Finally, in the late afternoon, Don will be reviewing the recent equipment malfunction and deciding whether to deploy extra people to get the equipment running as soon as possible. What a day!When Don meets with Phil to discuss Phil's output decline, in which management role will Don be operating?",
      "answer": "leader",
      "explanation": "A person who resolves conflicts and 'fixes' tricky situations that involve people is being a leader. Don's ability to point out Phil's failings while at the same time exhorting Phil to do better in the future is evidence of Don's leadership talent. Since both disseminator and spokesperson focus on informational rather than motivational issues, neither matches Don's role in this task. Being a figurehead is an interpersonal role, but it does not involve ironing out interpersonal problems, so it is not the correct choice here."
    },
    {
      "question": "When Don reviews the equipment malfunction, what management role will he play in deciding whether to bring in extra people?",
      "answer": "resource allocator",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Michelle is the general manager of a power plant. This morning, she will meet with city officials to discuss environmental issues. After the meeting, she will confer with the plant's section managers to address the concerns of the city representatives. This afternoon, Michelle will meet with a team leader to go over a complaint filed by an employee. After the complaint meeting, Michelle plans to spend time in the library and on the Internet researching new technologies that can be used to improve the performance of her plant.When Michelle addresses a complaint filed by an employee, she is performing which management role?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "A complaint is clearly a type of disturbance, so in addressing an employee's complaint, Michelle is functioning as a disturbance handler. None of the other roles—resource allocator, liaison, or figurehead—involve addressing problems directly or 'fixing' situations, so the correct choice here is disturbance handler."
    },
    {
      "question": "Michelle is the general manager of a power plant. This morning, she will meet with city officials to discuss environmental issues. After the meeting, she will confer with the plant's section managers to address the concerns of the city representatives. This afternoon, Michelle will meet with a team leader to go over a complaint filed by an employee. After the complaint meeting, Michelle plans to spend time in the library and on the Internet researching new technologies that can be used to improve the performance of her plant.When Michelle learns from city officials about how her plant's operations may be affecting the environment, she is performing which management role?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "In meeting with officials outside of the organization, Michelle is providing a link to the outside world, or functioning as a liaison. Of the other choices given, leader and resource allocator do not involve communication with the outside world. An entrepreneur may connect with the outside world, but Michelle is not functioning as an entrepreneur because she is not looking for business opportunities. So liaison is the only choice that makes sense here."
    },
    {
      "question": "Michelle is the general manager of a power plant. This morning, she will meet with city officials to discuss environmental issues. After the meeting, she will confer with the plant's section managers to address the concerns of the city representatives. This afternoon, Michelle will meet with a team leader to go over a complaint filed by an employee. After the complaint meeting, Michelle plans to spend time in the library and on the Internet researching new technologies that can be used to improve the performance of her plant.When Michelle meets with the section managers to brief them on the concerns of the city officials, which management role is she performing?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Michelle's meeting with the section managers is one in which she is dispensing information or functioning as a disseminator. Michelle is connecting with others here, but she is not a liaison because she is connecting within the organization, not outside of it. Michelle is neither addressing a problem nor mediating between parties so she is not functioning in the role of disturbance handler or negotiator."
    },
    {
      "question": "Michelle is the general manager of a power plant. This morning, she will meet with city officials to discuss environmental issues. After the meeting, she will confer with the plant's section managers to address the concerns of the city representatives. This afternoon, Michelle will meet with a team leader to go over a complaint filed by an employee. After the complaint meeting, Michelle plans to spend time in the library and on the Internet researching new technologies that can be used to improve the performance of her plant.When Michelle spends time searching for new technologies for her plant, she is performing which management role?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Michelle's meeting with the section managers is one in which she is dispensing information or functioning as a disseminator. Michelle is connecting with others here, but she is not a liaison because she is connecting within the organization, not outside of it. Michelle is neither addressing a problem nor mediating between parties so she is not functioning in the role of disturbance handler or negotiator."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT an example of a decisional role according to Mintzberg?",
      "answer": "spokesperson",
      "explanation": "Mintzberg sees entrepreneur, disturbance handler, and resource allocator as decisional roles. The entrepreneur must decide which opportunity to select. A disturbance handler must stand in judgment of individuals in a conflict. A resource allocator must decide how to divide resources. Mintzberg sees a spokesperson having a primary function of communicating what has already been decided."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which set of skills would you expect the President of the United States to be least in need of?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "A president undoubtedly needs all four skills, but not in equal quantities. Political skills are obviously required for a politician to get elected and mobilize alliances once elected. Interpersonal skills would be critical to persuading people to support one's point of view. Conceptual skills would be required for analyzing difficult situations and navigating through dangerous political waters. If any skill would be less needed, it would be technical, as technical matters for a president would likely be covered by subordinates."
    },
    {
      "question": "Michelle is the general manager of a power plant. This morning, she will meet with city officials to discuss environmental issues. After the meeting, she will confer with the plant's section managers to address the concerns of the city representatives. This afternoon, Michelle will meet with a team leader to go over a complaint filed by an employee. After the complaint meeting, Michelle plans to spend time in the library and on the Internet researching new technologies that can be used to improve the performance of her plant.Which type of management skill does Michelle use most during the day?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Three of Michelle's activities for the day require interpersonal skills—meeting with the city officials, meeting with the section managers, and handling the employee's complaint. Michelle's research is the only activity she carries out that does not require some measure of interpersonal skill. None of the other skills—conceptual, informational, or political—is used as frequently."
    },
    {
      "question": "A good manager considers the interests of all stakeholders equally when making an important decision.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": "A manager should consider the interests of all stakeholders, but different stakeholders merit more or less consideration depending who they are and what their relationship is to the organization."
    },
    {
      "question": "All of the following show why corporate rituals can be valuable in a corporate culture EXCEPT ________.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Rituals have been shown to be valuable for initiations, reinforcing attitudes and values, and conveying important ideas and ideals. One would hope that rituals would not be used to intimidate or stifle the instincts of an employee in any way, making the choice regarding that issue the correct response."
    },
    {
      "question": "An industry with a dynamic business environment that is also highly complex faces the maximum amount of environmental uncertainty.            ",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": "This kind of business corresponds to cell 4 in the environmental uncertainty matrix"
    },
    {
      "question": "Environmental complexity refers to the number of components that an organization must deal with.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": "Complexity refers to how many competitors, customers, suppliers, and other entities a company must deal with."
    },
    {
      "question": "Generation X-ers are generally the children of the Baby Boomers.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": "Gen Yers, born between 1978 and 1994, are generally the children of the Baby Boomers."
    },
    {
      "question": "Given a choice, managers would prefer to operate in an environment that has a minimum of uncertainty.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": "A dynamic environment that is also highly complex is very difficult to plan for and very difficult for decision making."
    },
    {
      "question": "How are the 'Post-Millennials' likely to be different from previous generations?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "The Post-Millennials have grown up with sophisticated technology. Rather than purchase music albums, for example, this cohort grew up with customizeable iPods and other devices that allowed them to individualize their experience. Similarly, this group tends to watch TV not in the living room when it is being broadcast, but as an individual event that they experience when they want to see it on their computers."
    },
    {
      "question": "How is a corporate ritual different from a corporate story or legend?",
      "answer": "A ritual does not attempt to teach a specific lesson while a story or legend does.",
      "explanation": "Both rituals and stories and legends are meant to be taken seriously. The two are different, however, in that a story or legend typically has a specific point it wants to make or a lesson it wants to teach. A ritual, on the other hand, is more concerned with conveying the company identity rather than communicating any specific message."
    },
    {
      "question": "Sony Corporation's focus on product innovation is an example of which of the following dimensions of organizational culture?            ",
      "answer": "risk tolerance",
      "explanation": "Innovation is a creative process, and being creative almost always involves making mistakes and taking risks. This makes 'risk tolerance' the correct choice and eliminates the other items as they do not deal with innovation or creativity."
    },
    {
      "question": "Technology has changed the way managers manage by forcing them to keep track of employees in remote locations at all times of the day and night.Select",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": "Managers in today's world must stay in touch with employees who can be located anywhere in the world and may have problems at any time of any day."
    },
    {
      "question": "The age of a population is one of its most important demographics.            ",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": "Different generations have different styles, tastes, and goals that affect how business is done."
    },
    {
      "question": "The business world cannot count on regulation to reform the economy.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": "Regulation can go only so far. In order for true reform to occur, business people need to assume a new mindset."
    },
    {
      "question": "The cell phone industry faces a stable business environment.            ",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": "The cell phone industry faces constant and rapid change, making it a dynamic business environment."
    },
    {
      "question": "The components of an organization's external environment include a technological component and a political component.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": "The technological component may include such things as new software, while the political component may include office holders who directly affect a company's business."
    },
    {
      "question": "The culture of an organization is analogous to the ________ of an individual.",
      "answer": "personality",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The Daily Recorder is considering charging online readers a flat fee for access to the news on their computers and electronic devices. Which stakeholder should the paper NOT worry about informing?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "The paper certainly should inform all readers of the change as a courtesy. The paper's unions also may be informed, though they may be only indirectly or marginally affected by the decision. One constituency that should not be told about the change is the paper's competitor. The less that The Daily Sun knows about the change, the more of a competitive advantage that the paper will get out of the change."
    },
    {
      "question": "The Daily Recorder is considering raising its price from 60 cents to 75 cents. Which stakeholders should it consider most in making this decision?",
      "answer": "its customers",
      "explanation": "Though all stakeholders should be considered in an important decision, in most cases some stakeholders should be regarded as more critical than others. In this case, the customers who will be expected to pay the extra cost should be considered first and foremost."
    },
    {
      "question": "The external environment of an organization includes factors and forces that can affect how the organization operates.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": "The external environment includes any outside agent that can influence the performance of the organization."
    },
    {
      "question": "The greater the environmental uncertainty, the more an organization needs to become ________.",
      "answer": "organic",
      "explanation": "Increased uncertainty in a business environment requires an organization to be more flexible and adaptable—in other words, more organic. High uncertainty would militate against being more mechanistic, and it would have little influence on the stability of an organization or the degree to which it was 'high-tech.'"
    },
    {
      "question": "The original source of an organization's culture usually reflects the vision and attitudes of ________.",
      "answer": "??",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The sociocultural component of the external environment of an organization includes trends and traditions, but not basic attitudes and values.            ",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": "The sociocultural component of the external environment includes all beliefs and values as well as attitudes and behavioral patterns."
    },
    {
      "question": "The symbolic view of management holds that an organization's performance is based solely on the decisions of managers.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": "The omnipotent view of management holds that an organization's performance is based solely on the decisions of managers."
    },
    {
      "question": "Theodore and Janice have formed TJ Soft, an entrepreneurial venture to develop games and other kinds of software for consumers. Theodore has just gotten wind from a highly reliable source that games involving animals and ecosystems are likely to be extremely 'hot' in the coming year. Theodore is excited because TJ Soft has two games in development that fit the animal/eco niche perfectly. Which component of the external environment will affect TJ Soft the most in this situation?            ",
      "answer": "the sociocultural component",
      "explanation": "The demographic component, political component, and global components are likely to play only marginal roles in the success of TJ Soft's new games. What will make a difference is that the assessment of public taste—the appetite for a specific kind of game—has been correctly assessed. This assessment employs the sociocultural component of the external managerial environment"
    },
    {
      "question": "Theodore and Janice have formed TJ Soft, an entrepreneurial venture to develop games and other kinds of software for consumers. Theodore has just gotten wind from a highly reliable source that Congress is likely to take action in the coming year to ban violent games. TJ Soft has several games that could be considered violent. Which component of the external environment will affect TJ Soft the most in this situation?",
      "answer": "the political/legal component",
      "explanation": "The demographic component, technological component, and economic components are unlikely to play large roles in this situation. What will make a difference is the political component since Congress is a political entity and the problem that the company has is based on a law that was passed."
    },
    {
      "question": "Theodore and Janice have formed TJ Soft, an entrepreneurial venture to develop games and other kinds of software for consumers. Theodore has just gotten wind that engineers have developed a new computer system that works like the devices shown in the Steven Spielberg movie Minority Report in which users can control a sophisticated computer using their hands in midair. Janice sees this development as highly important to new games for TJ Soft. Which component of the external environment will affect TJ Soft the most in this situation?",
      "answer": "the technological component            ",
      "explanation": "The sociocultural component, political component, and global components are likely to play only marginal roles in the success of TJ Soft's new games. What will make a difference is a technology developme"
    },
    {
      "question": "Theodore and Janice have formed TJ Soft, an entrepreneurial venture to develop games and other kinds of software for consumers. Theodore has just read an article that describes the explosion of computer games among young people in India using cell phones and simple computers. This generation in India has well over 300 million people in it, and if TJ Soft can capture just a tiny portion of that market it will be highly successful. Which component of the external environment will affect TJ Soft the most in this situation?",
      "answer": "the demographic component",
      "explanation": "The political component, technological component, and legal components are unlikely to play large roles in this situation. What will make a difference is the demographic component since the large population of potential customers in India is the critical factor in this situation."
    },
    {
      "question": "Theodore and Janice have formed TJ Soft, an entrepreneurial venture to develop games and other kinds of software for consumers. Theodore has just read an article that says that the low interest rates that currently prevail are likely to end in the coming months. Theodore thinks that TJ Soft may need to apply for a loan now to avoid high costs later. Which component of the external environment will affect TJ Soft the most in this situation?",
      "answer": "the economic component",
      "explanation": "The global component, technological component, and sociocultural components are unlikely to play large roles in this situation. What will make a difference is the economic component since interest rates are a function of the economy."
    },
    {
      "question": "What determines whether an organization has a strong culture or a weak culture?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "??"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do most high performing companies have in common when it comes to stakeholder relationships?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "High performing companies tend to be aware that the more input they get from stakeholders of every variety, the better off they are. Keeping stakeholders as informed as possible leads to better relationships and more input for how the company can succeed in a highly competitive marketplace. High performing companies recognize that they can't operate in a vacuum, and important decisions must be considered from every angle before they are made."
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the story of 3M employee Art Fry inventing the Post-it® note to make church hymns communicate to 3M employees?",
      "answer": "Creativity is important",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "What will cause countries such as Denmark to shrink with respect to the size of their economy, relative to other nations?            ",
      "answer": "low birth rate",
      "explanation": "Shrinking populations augur a smaller share of the world's economic pie in developed European nations such as Denmark, Norway, and Belgium. Social safety nets and welfare payments have little to do with the size of the economies of these nations, which, incidentally, are quite healthy despite the low growth rate of their populations."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which kind of organizational culture do the following values describe? 1. Don't be lazy or sloppy. 2. It's better to try a good idea and fail then to stick with a bad idea. 3. When you think your product is perfect, go back and try to make it better.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "The company conveys its attitude toward risk and innovation by stating that failure is 'allowed' as long a person fails when attempting to implement a good idea. The company conveys its high standards by saying that 'perfect' is not good enough."
    },
    {
      "question": "Siia pilt juurde Which kind of company has the lowest amount of environmental uncertainty in the environmental uncertainty matrix?",
      "answer": "cell 1 ??",
      "explanation": "Cell 1 identifies a company in an industry with little innovation and no new competitors that also has few components (customers, suppliers, etc.) in its environment. An example of this kind of company is the Zippo lighter company, which has a few simple products, few competitors, and few components to deal with in its industry."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which kind of company would be less likely to fire its CEO after a poor performance?",
      "answer": "a company with a symbolic view of management",
      "explanation": "A company with an omnipotent view of management would tend to hold its leaders responsible for failure and would therefore be more likely to fire its leaders after a poor performance. A company with a symbolic view of management would tend to see the leader's role as less consequential to success or failure, and therefore there would be no reason to fire the CEO if he or she otherwise was doing a good job."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which kind of culture most affects the way managers plan?",
      "answer": "A strong organizational culture helps guide the way managers plan.",
      "explanation": "A strong organizational culture helps guide the way for all of the primary managerial functions—planning, organizing, leading, and controlling. Rather than make decisions that are independent of organizational values, a strong culture instills those values in its managers and guides them on their way to planning, organizing, leading, and controlling."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which managerial controlling decision is most affected by organizational culture?",
      "answer": "how much to empower employees??",
      "explanation": "Environmental scanning is a part of the planning function of a manager. Anticipating risk is part of the planning function. Determining employee autonomy is part of the organizing function. Structuring employee evaluations is part of the organizing function of a manager"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which managerial organizing decision is most affected by organizational culture?",
      "answer": "whether workers should work individually or in teams",
      "explanation": "Environmental scanning is a part of the planning function of a manager. Handling employee disagreements is part of the leading function. Structuring evaluations is part of the controlling function. Assigning employees to work in teams or as individuals is part of the organizing function of a manager."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which managerial planning decision is most affected by organizational culture?            ",
      "answer": "the degree of risk that plans contain",
      "explanation": "Autonomy falls into the category of organizing while empowerment is a controlling decision. Leadership style is categorized in the leading function. That leaves risk, which is a part of the planning function of a manager as the correct response."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following best defines environmental uncertainty?",
      "answer": "the amount of change and complexity in an organization's external environment",
      "explanation": "Environmental uncertainty is a measure of two things: change in an organization's environment with respect to its market, its products, its position in the market, and so on; and the amount of complexity it faces in its market as measured by the number of competitors, customers, suppliers, and so on."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following identifies one reason why managers should NOT put time into managing stakeholder relationships?",
      "answer": "Managing stakeholder relationships can lead to less predictability of environmental changes.",
      "explanation": "Managing stakeholder relationships can lead to more, not less, predictability of environmental changes. If stakeholders are aware of the actions and decisions that the organization is going to undertake, they are less likely to feel 'surprised' by those actions and decisions and more likely to become cooperative with the organization itself. Stakeholders who are not kept 'in the loop' are likely to feel resentful toward the organization and more likely to take actions that are against the organization's better interests."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an internal stakeholder for the newspaper, The Daily Recorder?",
      "answer": "shareholders in The Daily Sun",
      "explanation": "The various parts of The Daily Sun are at best external stakeholders in The Daily Recorder since they belong to an organization that is a competitor of the paper. Similarly, the city council would be considered an external stakeholder, not an internal stakeholder. That leaves the shareholders of the paper itself—they are internal stakeholders."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to be considered a stakeholder for a newspaper company, The Daily Recorder?",
      "answer": "critics who claim that all newspapers are biased and dishonest",
      "explanation": "Stakeholders include anyone who is affected by the organization's decisions or actions. So both a paper boy and customers are affected by the paper. Critics who criticize the paper from afar are not stakeholders because what they do is not significantly affected by anything that the paper does."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a common way in which corporate cultures are transmitted to employees?",
      "answer": "formal culture meetings",
      "explanation": "Corporate culture gets handed down through stories, rituals, and material symbols, but not formal culture meetings. The dissemination of cultural values is almost always an indirect process in which meaning is inferred from a story, action, or even something as small as a facial expression."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT considered to be a characteristic of organizational culture?",
      "answer": "purchasing policies",
      "explanation": "Organizational culture involves attitudes, how competitive employees are, and how discerning and tidy employees are. Organizational culture does not involve purchasing, making 'purchasing policies' the correct response for this question."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not involved with the demographic component of an organization's external environment?",
      "answer": "values",
      "explanation": "The demographic component of an organization's external environment involves issues that relate to broad population characteristics such as age, income, number of people in a family, education level, and so on. Values are not measurable on this broad level, so they are not considered a demographic trait."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following most accurately reflects the difference between strong cultures and weak cultures?",
      "answer": "Company values are more deeply held and widely shared in strong cultures than in weak cultures.",
      "explanation": "Strong cultures are common in successful organizations, making the choice regarding weak cultures being found in most successful organizations incorrect. The choice regarding strong cultures having less influence is incorrect because strong cultures have more impact on individuals than weak cultures. Strong cultures encouraging employee innovation is incorrect because a strong culture may or may not encourage innovation. This leaves the choice regarding company values being more deeply held and widely shared as the correct response, as it accurately states that strong cultures imprint themselves more deeply into individuals than weak cultures."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following phrases best characterizes the culture of an organization?",
      "answer": "how things are done around here            ",
      "explanation": "The most apt phrase for an organizational culture is 'how things are done around here.' An organizational culture is not thought to be official in any way, efficient, or comprised of a set of guidelines to light the way to the future. Instead, the organizational culture is a set of values and attitudes, making 'how things are done around here' a perfect description"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following provides the best illustration of technology transforming how managers manage in the workplace?",
      "answer": "Managers oversee very small clerical and secretarial staffs.",
      "explanation": "Where managers once needed to manage extremely large clerical and secretarial staffs, many clerical jobs have now been replaced due to technological innovations. For example, much of the typing and record-keeping that was once done by several workers is now done by a single worker using a sophisticated computer program. Things such as design teams have decreased rather than increased in size because a single person can now accomplish the work of many designers using modern computer design programs. At the same time, design teams require much less, not much more, supervision in today's business climate."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements about organizational culture is correct?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "A strong culture essentially takes the place of written rules and regulations. Rather than need to consult written documents, employees in a strong culture simply refer to the unwritten precepts that the culture provides. In organizations with truly strong cultures, there is agreement with respect to values so this system works well."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following views of management would agree with the statement that managers should not be held accountable for changing global economic conditions?",
      "answer": "the symbolic view",
      "explanation": "The symbolic view of management contends that a manager's ability to affect the organization's outcomes is constrained by external factors such as the economy."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which statement about the external environment and employment is true?            ",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "During boom times, unemployment drops and wages tend to rise, improving the fortunes of the working public. During recessions and downturns, the opposite takes place: unemployment rises and wages tend to stagnate or drop. Overall, jobs closely correlate with the state of the economy."
    },
    {
      "question": "Why were the Baby Boomers so much more influential than other generations with respect to changing tastes and culture?",
      "answer": "The Baby Boomers were a much larger group than other generations.",
      "explanation": "Being coherent or free-spirited did not have the impact on culture the sheer size of the Baby Boom generation did. Because of its large size, the generation dictated almost every cultural trend and style for over forty years"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Hawthorne Studies refer to __________ conducted at the Hawthorne Works of the Western Electric Company.",
      "answer": "??",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Maslow’s theory of human needs is consistent with which area of management thought?",
      "answer": "??",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The three branches of the classical approach to management are __________.            ",
      "answer": "Scientific management, administrative principles, and bureaucratic organization.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The practical lessons of scientific management include all of the following EXCEPT:",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Henri Fayol, the five rules of management are __________.",
      "answer": " Foresight, organization, command, coordination, and control.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Weber’s conception of bureaucratic organizations included all of the following characteristics         EXCEPT:",
      "answer": "Careers based on social and/or political connections.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The behavioral (or human resource) approach to management basically assumes that __________.",
      "answer": "People at work will seek satisfying social relationships, respond to group pressures, and search for personal fulfillment.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Even though the way we manage our work and our organizations is changing - managers today can benefit from studying the history of management thought.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A key lesson from the Hawthorne studies is that people’s feelings, attitudes, and relationships with co-workers have very little influence their performance as compared with compensation and incentives.",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Management science refers to the scientific application of mathematical techniques to management problems and decision-making.            ",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Contingency thinking involves matching responses to the unique problems and opportunities posed by different situations and by individual and environmental differences.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Many modern management concepts have parallels in some of the historical management writings, and contemporary managers are trying to perfect many ideas that have deep historical roots.            ",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The three branches of classical management approaches are scientific management, theory x and y, and bureaucratic organization.            ",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A major assumption of classical approaches to management is that people are much more driven by human concerns for other workers than by the need to achieve personal gain.            ",
      "answer": "false",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A concurrent control system focuses on __________.            ",
      "answer": "Work throughputs",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Controlling is defined as:",
      "answer": "A process of measuring performance and taking action to ensure desired results.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In the control process, _________ must be accurate enough to identify significant difference between what is really taking place and what was originally planned.",
      "answer": "Measurement",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Internal control occurs when __________.",
      "answer": "Computers are used to monitor performance inside the organization ?????",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "John generates a cost report that displays overruns to the budget on a project completed during the prior month. This is an example of which type of control?",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "cost control is the wrong answer, so maybe answer is managerial or feedback control"
    },
    {
      "question": "Managers should be careful in their use of the word “control” because __________.",
      "answer": "The word has a negative connotation.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The four steps of the control process are: establish performance objectives and standards; measure actual performance; compare actual performance with objectives and standards; and _________.",
      "answer": "Take corrective action as needed.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The purpose of controlling is to __________.",
      "answer": "Make sure plans are achieved and that actual performance meets or surpasses objectives.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following steps in the control process is assisted by a manager’s effective planning?",
      "answer": "Comparing actual performance with objectives and standards. ??",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ measure performance results in terms of quantity, quality, cost, or time of accomplished work.",
      "answer": "Output standards.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The three variables that assist in determining a leader’s situational control according to Fiedler’s contingency theory are:            ",
      "answer": "Position power, task structure, and leader-member relations.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Janet is a supervisor of a group of bank tellers. Her subordinates are highly supportive, their jobs are well defined, and she has clear authority to evaluate and reward their performance. Which of the following leadership styles would be most recommended for Janet based upon Fiedler’s theory?            ",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Relationship-oriented isnot the correct answer"
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ is the process of inspiring others to work hard to accomplish important tasks.",
      "answer": "Leadership",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The management function of leading is BEST described by which of the following?",
      "answer": "Building commitment and enthusiasm for people to apply their talents to help accomplish plans            ",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Reward power, coercive power, and legitimate power are different types of __________.            ",
      "answer": "Position power.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "When Laura, a department store manager, instructs her employees to do something simply because she is the boss and therefore the other person must do as asked, she is trying to use __________ power to influence the other person’s behavior.            ",
      "answer": "legitimate",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Vision, which is frequently associated with effective leadership, refers to __________.            ",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "The ability to spontaneously take charge in a group situation. - is not the correct answer"
    },
    {
      "question": "Personal traits that are common among successful leaders include all of the following EXCEPT:",
      "answer": "Cognitive ability and business knowledge ???",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ attempt to answer the question: When and under what circumstances is a particular leadership style preferable to others?",
      "answer": "Contingency approaches to leadership.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The three bases of position power are reward, coercive, and legitimate.",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Trait theories of leadership address the question of: 'What personal characteristics separate effective leaders from ineffective leaders?'",
      "answer": "true",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "An unfulfilled physiological or psychological desire is called a(n):",
      "answer": "Need",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Expanding the content of a job to include work planning and evaluating duties that are normally performed by the supervisor is an example of which of the following?",
      "answer": "Job enrichment",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In the two-factor theory of motivation, a __________ is found in job content, such as a sense of achievement, recognition, responsibility, advancement, or personal growth.",
      "answer": "Satisfier factor.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Job design uses the insights of __________ to attain high levels of both job satisfaction and job performance.",
      "answer": "Motivation theories.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Kathy notices that most of her coworkers take extended lunch breaks. Kathy doesn’t do this, but feels she is therefore justified in working a little less hard during the day. Kathy’s decision to work “less hard” is best explained by the __________ theory of motivation.",
      "answer": "Equity",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Managers who choose to employ the two-factor theory should __________.            ",
      "answer": "??",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Organizations that employ individuals on a part-time and temporary basis to supplement a permanent workforce are utilizing __________.",
      "answer": "Contingency workers.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The belief that work motivation is determined by individual beliefs regarding effort-performance relationships and the desirability of possible rewards and other work-related outcomes is called.",
      "answer": "Expectancy theory.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ is a work arrangement that allows at least a portion of scheduled work hours to be completed outside of the office.",
      "answer": "",
      "explanation": "Flexible working hours isnot a correct answer"
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ provide direction to people in their work, clarify performance expectations, establish a frame of reference for feedback, and provide a foundation for behavioral self-management.",
      "answer": "Task goals.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ refers to trust, respect, and integrity in the eyes of others.Select one:",
      "answer": "Credibility",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A successful manager must possess:",
      "answer": "Both verbal and written skills.            ",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In regard to management styles:            ",
      "answer": "Different styles apply to different situations.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Social networking is",
      "answer": "Linking with other people.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The communication process is comprised of all of the following elements EXCEPT?",
      "answer": "Goal (found in google)",
      "explanation": "answer is goal or channel"
    },
    {
      "question": "The process of helping the source of a message say what he or she really means is called __________.",
      "answer": "Active listening.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements accurately describes communication effectiveness?Select one:",
      "answer": "Effective communication occurs when the sender’s intended message and the receiver’s interpreted meaning of that message are identical.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ is getting someone else to support the message being presented.",
      "answer": "Persuasion",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ refers to trust, respect, and integrity in the eyes of others",
      "answer": "Credibility",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Susan prefers to lead her department by allowing her employees the right to make decisions and take action. Susan is utilizing ___________.            ",
      "answer": "What the manager should do.            ",
      "explanation": "Empowerment"
    },
    {
      "question": "The line of authority that vertically links all persons with successively higher levels of management is the __________.",
      "answer": "Chain of command.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The number of persons reporting directly to a single manager is referred to as __________.",
      "answer": "Span of control.            ",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The organizational design that is highly bureaucratic in nature is called the __________ design.",
      "answer": "Mechanistic",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The process of grouping work positions into formal teams and departments, and then linking them together within the organization is known as __________.",
      "answer": "Departmentalization",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The __________ of the organization represents the way the organization is intended to function in terms of division of work, supervisory relationships, communication channels, major subunits, and levels of management.",
      "answer": "Formal structure",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "There are many reasons for organizing a business but all revolve around three common types of traditional organizational structures are __________.",
      "answer": "Functional, divisional, and matrix.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Triple Z Inc. is a new company that is contemplating the type of organizational design to use in its operations and is considering a design that is characterized by decentralization, wider spans of control, and few rules and procedures. Triple Z is considering which type of design?:",
      "answer": "Organic",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "When an organization chart shows vice presidents of marketing, manufacturing, finance, and human resources reporting directly to the president of a company, the top management group is organized as a __________ structure.            ",
      "answer": "Functional",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "When organizations grow in size, adding levels of management and thereby lengthening the chain of command, they tend to get __________.            ",
      "answer": "Taller",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the most accurate description regarding the purpose of an organization structure?",
      "answer": "To divide up and coordinate resources and tasks to be done for performance success",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "XYZ Marketing creates teams of employees from varying departments within the organization when working on projects for their clients. This combination of members from different areas of work responsibility is an example of:",
      "answer": "Cross-functional team",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ is the system of tasks, workflows, reporting relationships, and communication channels that link together the work of diverse individuals and groups",
      "answer": "Organization structure.",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ structures group together jobs and activities that are being performed in the same location.",
      "answer": "Geographical",
      "explanation": ""
    }
  ]
}
